RAHUL MONDAL

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

+91 8777036966 rrmondal12@gmail.com portfolio-website

SKILLS

Rust (Actix, Axum, Yew, Tauri)
JS (Node, React)
Python (TensorFlow)

MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Kubernetes, **Docker**, Okteto,

WebRTC, WebSocket, JWT, ProtoBuf, gRPC, Hashing, Encryption, Asym-Cryptography

EDUCATION

Future Institute of Tech.

2017-2021

Computer Science &
Engineering

Sonarpur Sikhsa Sadan 2015-2017 Higher Secondary (XII)

Harinavi D. V. A. S. High School **2014-2015**

Secondary (X)

PROFILE

Aspiring and versatile software artisan with a flair for AI and over 3 year of experience. Eagerly pursuing a riveting software development role where creativity meats innovation, to craft cutting-edge solutions and contribute to transformative projects.

EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Web Developer (Rust)

Freelance | Mar.2024 - Present

- Developed a high-performance Exchange-Engine using Rust and WebSockets, enabling seamless real-time transactions between buyers and sellers on specific client request.
- Optimized the matching process for buyers and sellers, achieving an ~80% in search time by implementing a simple **HashMap** based solution.

Software Developer (RUST)

Digital Aptech Pvt. Ltd. | Oct.2023 - Mar.2024

- Developed a scalable chat-widget from the ground up using **Yew.rs** integrating advanced tech stacks including **WebSocket** & **WebRTC**.
- Spearheaded the migration of over five microservices from **Warp** to **Axum**, enhancing application performance and scalability while implementing more than **100** test cases to boost code reliability by reducing bugs.
- Leveraged **Docker** and **Kubernetes** for seamless container orchestration, deploying applications using **Helm** charts, resulting in improved scalability and reliability.
- Implemented CI/CD pipelines with **Okteto**, streamlining development workflows and accelerating code delivery by ~30%.
- Collaborated closely with the client and a three-person team to build a reliable product, assisting in developing a microservice utilizing gRPC to establish WebSocket channels.

Software Developer (Rust)

Rapid Innovation | Jan.2022 - Sept.2023

- Developed a desktop app with **Rust** (**Tauri**, **Actix-Web**) to monitor remote employees, enhancing productivity.
- Utilized **MongoDB**, **AWS S3** and vanilla.js, later integrating **React.js** for the web version, now supporting over 200+ remote employees.
- Optimized databases performance by 'indexing' and utilizing compressed JPEG files instead of PNGs, resulting in over \$350 monthly savings on database billing.